# Ben Klein UX/UI Designer

User Experience Designer with a background in animation and storyboarding. Expert storyteller experienced in analyzing a problem from various angles to come up with an array of creative solutions quickly and presenting them in an aesthetic way, while keeping the client's and user's needs and goals at the centre of the process.

#### **UX/UI Projects**

### Flash | UX/UI Designer | Language Learning App

Luxembourg | May 2021- May 2021

 Applied a user-centered design process to design a modern-day flashcard app starting with user research and ending with a high-fidelity prototype

# Nonna | UX/UI designer | Inclusive Cooking App

Cambridge | June 2021- November 2021

 Applied a user-centered design process to design a inclusive cooking app starting with user research and ending with an interactive, high-fidelity prototype

#### **Relevant Work Experience**

#### Art & Design Teacher | Lycée de Garçons

Luxembourg | August 2020- July 2021

- Boosted students' and faculty's work flow by 50% by teaching them on how to use a wide range of digital editing and drawing softwares
- Spearheaded and organized a design program for students and faculty by effectively mediating between and bringing together different departments
- Guided, motivated and critiqued students during homework assignments and collaborative projects pushing them to create some of that year's best work

#### Storyboard artist | CG LUX & PTD

Luxembourg | October 2019 - February 2020

- Assisted and motivated the director and fellow storyboard artists to translate the script into a coherent vision
- Maximized the re-use of 2D backgrounds by 30% helping the 3D modelers stay within budget and on time
- Composed model sheets in my free time to speed up pre-production and to save the team money and time

#### **Contract storyboard artist | SONY Playstation**

San Francisco | 2016-2018

- Worked on several commercials for different Playstation platforms ranging from PS4, to PS Pro over to Playstation VR for their presence at E3 helping them win several big contracts
- Collaborated closely with producer and art director in order to bring their exact vision to life under very tight deadlines

#### **Contact Info**

- benkleindesigns.com
- •thebenklein@gmail.com
- •+352 661 402 461
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/benklein-83066945/

#### **Soft Skills**

- Empathy
- Active listening
- Creative Problem solving
- Quick ideation skills

#### **UX/UI Skills**

- Primary Research
- Secondary Research
- User Personas
- User Journeys
- Usability Analysis
- Storyboarding
- Sitemaps
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- UI Design
- Style Guides

#### **Tools**

- PhotoshopCSS
- •Illustrator •Javascript
- Adobe XD
- Figma
- Marvel
- Sketch
- InDesign
- Atom
- •Html

#### **Education**

# **UX Design Certificate** CareerFoundry

Berlin 2021

## Bachelor in 2D Animation

Academy of Art University San Francisco 2014